This story is fiction. The names of people,
places and groups are imaginary.
Obey traffic rules and drive safely.
Initial
Raise up your hands　高く [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands high.
(Everybody now raise your hands)
Take hold, there's a brand new tomorrow.
掴め　Brand new tomorrow [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
風の中で　自分を知る　ずっと最高のDreamだろう
It's a beautiful eternal dream...
...where you learn about yourself.
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh raise up you can't stop
Oh, raise up your hands now.
If you think you're lucky just to be alive go for the highest stake in the gamble.
生きてるだけで何やろうかな
Gamble on　迫る鼓動にテンバリ
同じMission　同じ一生
Same mission creates similar lives.
But your passion for your dream will make a difference.
どんだけ夢熱いかが勝負だろ
You can never use the escalator.
Escalator　無しの永遠
But you can build up your strength, yeah yeah.
足腰鍛え　Let's begin yeah
You must eventually climb the stairs.
どうせのぼる階段
心こっちにCustomizeしちゃえばいい
Customize them the way you like.
Intense days go by.
削られて　過ぎる毎日[But you know]
Intense days go by. (But you know?)
攻めがいのあるGameと　笑い飛ばして
Just laugh it off, 'cause it's a game worth competing.
Let's see how fast you can do it
Let's see how fast you can do it.
Raise up your hands　ずっと [Everybody gonna tell you I can't stop]
Raise up your hands forever.
(Everybody now raise your hands up)
Run, sleepless challenger.
走れ　Sleepless challenger [You don't stop]
(You don't stop)
今に生きる　理由を探す
It's a quest of the never-ending dream...
...where you now search for the reason to live.
夢尽きないQuest
(Let's go)
Oh[Let's go] Oh[Let's go]
Oh
Oh (Let's go)
Oh, raise up your hands now.
Oh raise up you can't stop
Way to go !
よっしゃあ
啓介さん先行逃げ切りのパーフェクトウイン
Keisuke managed to shake off
his opponent ! It's a perfect win !
すげー
Amazing !
７秒もの大差がつくなんて
A huge gap of 7 seconds...
怖いな　今日のダウンヒルは
Today's downhill is scary.
おっと　勘違いしてもらっちゃ困るぜ
Don't get me wrong.
俺が怖いと思うのは相手に対してじゃなく
I'm not afraid of my
opponent, but of myself.
自分に対してだ
走り始めたら　俺は多分自分の闘争心を抑えられないだろう
Once I start driving, I won't be
able to suppress my fighting spirit.
ギリギリまでマージンを削った　限界へ近づいていくアタックになると思う
I've gotta shave down the margin as much as possible.
My attack will be really close to my limit.
うまくゾーンに入ればいいが
I'll be alright within my zone,
but if I screw up, I'm done for.
しくじれば命取りだ
それを怖いと思わない自分が怖いのさ
But I'm not afraid of that,
and that's what scares me.
Omiya...
大宮さん
心配するな　うまくやれるはずだ
Don't worry. I should be
able to manage myself well.
俺のキャリアの中でも最高のパフォーマンスを今夜引き出してやる
I'll show you the best
performance of my career tonight.
向こうは一本目先行を選択したぞ
Our opponent chose the
lead position for the first run.
そうか
I see.
恐らく啓介の走りに触発されたんだろうな
He might have been
inspired by Keisuke's driving.
同じ作戦をそのままやりかえしてくるかもしれない
He might use the same strategy.
ここ一発のスピードには絶対に自信を持っているってことだ
In other words, he has absolute
confidence in his mad dash speed.
逆に　付け込むチャンスはそこにあるなら
In turn, we can take advantage of that.
いいか　後半の勾配のきつい空間が勝負所となるだろう
Listen. The steep area in the
second half will be the decisive point.
相手のスピードの変化を柔軟に吸収するんだ
Try to adapt to his
change in speed flexibly.
対応できると感じたら　一本目から行け
And if you feel you can make
a move, do it in this first run.
遠慮はいらないぜ
There's no need to hold back.
大宮智史だ
I'm Omiya Satoshi.
藤原拓海です
I'm Fujiwara Takumi.
負けんじゃねぇぞ　藤原
Don't lose, Fujiwara.
よし　カウント始めるぞ
Okay, I'm going to start the countdown !
Dead Line
ダウンヒルはどうなるかな
How do you read this downhill race ?
見事ヒルクライムを的中させた久保さんとしては
You hit the nail on the head
for the hill climb, Kubo.
いやー　こっちは分からん　俺にも読めませんわ
I have no idea this time.
It's unpredictable.
Omiya is definitely a first-class driver.
大宮というドライバーは確かに一流でっけどな
３　２　１　ゴー
Three...
Two...
One...
Go !
あのハチロクが余りに未知数ですねぇ
There are too many
unknowns about that Eight-Six.
えらい胡散臭いクルマに仕上がってるみたいやなぁ
There's something strange about that car.
おまけにあの若いドライバーがまた胡散臭い
And also something strange
about that young driver.
長いこと業界見てますけど　まずめったにお目にかかれないほど
I've been in this business for quite a while.
I can tell you he's a rare
breed with a unique style.
独特の世界観もっとる奴ですわ
Is he fast ?
速いか
Oh, sure.
そらもう
そのハチロクのドライバーにはあいつがついている
That Eight-Six driver is
backed by a certain someone.
高橋涼介がな
Takahashi Ryosuke.
この間から気にしてるようでっけど
You look like you've been troubled by him.
Do you have some kind of issue with him ?
何ぞ因縁でもあるんでっか　そのー
高橋涼介
Takahashi Ryosuke...
あるよ
I do. No, I mean...
いや 俺じゃなくて　もっと因縁のある奴がいる
There's someone else
who does more than I do.
NB8CロードスターとAE86トレノ
NB8C Roadster and AE86 Trueno...
...both have a light and compact body
with a small displacement NA engine.
共に軽量コンパクトな車体に小排気量NAエンジンを搭載し
軽快なフットワークを身上にワインディングロードを疾走する
They take advantage of their
agility to zip along a winding road.
そのコンセプトは共通だ
They share the same concept.
生まれた年代は異なるが
Even though they were made years
apart, their potential is very similar.
クルマのポテンシャルは限りなく接近したものになっている
That's why...
故に勝敗はそれぞれのドライバーの感性に委ねられる
...victory will be decided by the driver's instinct.
大宮智史というNB乗りの感性と藤原拓海というハチロク乗りの感性
The instincts of the NB driver,
Omiya Satoshi, and...
...the instincts of the Eight-Six
driver, Fujiwara Takumi.
どちらがよりクルマとの感性が合っているか
I think the result will be determined by
whose instincts match their car the best.
この勝負はそれが結果を分ける気がする
まるで生き物みたいだな　二人が乗っているクルマは
You make it sound
like both cars are alive.
そうかもしれないな　クルマからの一瞬の声を聞き逃した方が負ける
Maybe so.
The one who doesn't listen to the voice
of their car, even for a moment, will lose.
北関東エリアを負けなしで駆け抜けてきた伝説のチーム　プロジェクトDとは
Project D is a legendary team which swept
the northern Kanto area without any losses.
どんな走りなのか
どうせなら　それを後追いでじっくり見てみたい
It'd be wise to carefully observe how they drive from behind. That's what Kobayakawa thought.
小早川はそう考えた
俺にも同じ気持ちはある
I feel the same way.
だけどそこに落とし穴があった
But that was the pitfall.
相手を見るということは自分のペースを守れていないということなんだ
To observe your opponent
means you can't keep your pace.
あのハチロクを見ていくのは危険だ　そんな気がする
I sense it's risky to
just watch the Eight-Six.
これは俺の勘だ
I just have a hunch.
だから俺は先行で行く
That's why I chose the lead.
I'll keep my pace without
any obstacles ahead...
目前には何もない状況で自分のペースを作る
勝つためにだ
...in order to win.
ダウンヒルはどうなりますかね
I wonder how the downhill will develop.
簡単には勝たせてもらえないだろうな
I don't think we can win very easily.
ぶっちゃけレベル高いよ　ここの連中は
To be honest, our opponents' level is very high.
俺にしたって結果から見るほど楽な勝負じゃなかった
My race wasn't easy, even though it
may have looked like it from the result.
特に今　藤原が相手にしてる奴は手強いぜ
That guy Fujiwara's facing is especially tough.
公道ランナーとしてはほとんど完成の域に達してる奴だろうな
He must have perfected street driving.
そんなことが分かるんっすか
Can you tell ?
I can sense it...
俺には分かるんだ
藤原も　それは感じてるはずだ
...and Fujiwara...
...senses it as well.
隙がない　空間の全てが埋め尽くされてる感じだ
The entire space seems filled,
as if he's always on guard.
先行するNBがタメにタメて　どっかでスパートを駆けてくる
The leading NB will hold on, then it
will suddenly accelerate somewhere.
コースを知り尽くしてるだけに
As a local who knows this course best, he can
maintain his pace, which gives him an advantage.
ペースを握れる先行は地元にとっては有利なんだ
ってことは　勝負所は
So the decisive point will be...?
終盤の勾配がきつく　路面の荒れた区間だろうな
The steep, rough road
near the end of the course.
サスペンションの基本設計が古いハチロクにとっては不利な区間ですよね
That section is disadvantageous to the
Eight-Six because its suspension design is old.
まぁ　そういうことになるな
Well, that's true...
だけど不利なのは今に始まったことじゃない
But our disadvantage
didn't just begin tonight.
敢えて敵地で戦うのはレッドサンズ時代からの俺達のテーマだ
It's been our motto to fight on our
opponents' stage since the Red Suns days.
そうっすよ
Right.
アニキが練り上げたアウェイで戦いのノウハウはいつも完璧に機能する
My brother's carefully built know-how of fighting
those away races has always worked perfectly.
向こうがコースに特化したスペシャリストなら
If our opponent is a
specialist on this course...
こっちは敵地攻略に特化したスペシャルチームだ
...we're a special team organized
to attack enemy territories.
どっちのスピードが最終的には相手を上回るのか
Whoever is faster than the other...
それが結果的には全てだろ
That will be everything in the end.
高橋涼介という天才がいる限り　プロジェクトDに不可能はない
Nothing is impossible for Project D, as long
as we have the genius of Takahashi Ryosuke.
俺はそう思ってるけどな
I truly believe that.
近いぞ　もうすぐそこだ
They're close, almost at the corner.
中間地点のヘアピンに突っ込んでくるぞ
They're gonna dive into the mid-section hairpin.
来たぁ！　オーシ！
There they are !
Alright !
行っけー　大宮　本気出せー
Go, Omiya !
Throw everything you've got at 'em !
ハチロクなんかぶっちぎれー
Leave the Eight-Six in the dust !
ピタリとついたまま中間地点を通過していった
They've passed the mid-section, fighting tail to nose.
ここまでは同じ展開だ
It's developed the same
way up to this point.
どこかで必ずスパートを駆けてくるのは　分かってたんだ
I knew my opponent would
accelerate somewhere.
来る来ると思いながら　なかなか来ない相手に俺はじれていった
I was frustrated by my opponent, who didn't
make his move according to my predictions.
なぜだか　ひどく追い詰められた気持ちになっていた
For some reason, I felt cornered.
同じことはあのハチロクのドライバーにも起こっているんじゃないのか
The same thing must be
happening to that Eight-Six driver.
これは大宮のペースだ
In a situation where Omiya maintains his pace,
neither of them can ease up, even for a second.
一瞬たりとも　気が抜けない状況が続く
まだまだ半分終わったばかりだ
We're only at the halfway point.
テンションは目一杯振り切れそうだ
My tension is almost going off the scale.
だが　俺にはもう一段階ある
But I have one more level.
その闘争心のスイッチが切り替わる瞬間がどこかで来る
There will be a moment when
my fighting spirit turns on.
前よりも足太くなった気がするな
Seems like my legs got thicker...
この辺とか この辺とか
Here...and here.
筋トレやってるからかな
It must be because of the muscle training.
ドライバーの飛距離が伸びるのはいいけど
I can hit my drives farther, which is nice...
パンツのサイズ変わるのは微妙だ
...but my pants size changed, which isn't so nice.
夏休みだしな
I'm supposed to be on summer vacation.
たまには海とか行きたいな
I wish I could go to the beach once in a while...
拓海君とか
...with Takumi.
でも無理か忙しいから
That's impossible. I'm too busy...
拓海君は今頃神奈川でレースなんだよね
Takumi must be racing in Kanagawa now.
一度見てみたいけど
I want to see him race just once, but...
見たらきっと 凄く強いんだろうな
...that'll probably scare the hell out of me.
頑張ってね　拓海君
Do your best, Takumi.
Make sure you win.
絶対勝ってね
いいぞ
Good, I'm focused.
集中している
コースの攻略という観点から言えば
From a strategic point of view, I think
braking is the most important on the downhill.
ダウンヒルで一番重要なのは ブレーキングだと俺は思っている
平坦地に比べて
Stopping distance increases dramatically on the downhill
versus level ground, so one braking mistake is critical.
制動距離が飛躍的に伸びる下りでは
ブレーキングのミスは命取りになるし
サーキットのように距離を示してくれる看板のない真っ黒な公道で
Unlike circuits, public streets are dark without
any distance markers before each corner.
正確にブレーキングポイントを設定するには
So, to determine the precise braking point...
研ぎ澄まされた感覚だけが頼りなんだ
...you can only rely on your refined intuition.
目印は役に立たない
Landmarks are useless.
人間の脳の持っている潜在能力というのは
I'm constantly surprised by the
potential of the human brain.
つくづく凄いと思うよ
藤原特別に　ブレーキングの感覚が優れている
Fujiwara's braking sense is exceptional.
走り慣れた地元のドライバを相手にして
That's why he can keep winning on the downhill
against locals who are familiar with their course.
ダウンヒルで勝ち続きられるのはそのセンスのおかげなんだ
練習だけで身につくものじゃないよな
It's not something you can
acquire by just practicing.
間違いなく天性の物でしょうね
He's definitely a natural.
テールツーノーズで後ろから追うかけながら
You can figure out your opponent's driving skills by
watching how he brakes as you stay right on his tail.
ブレーキングを見ていれば
相手のドライバの実力はすぐに分かる
確かにな 難しいことじゃない
You're right. That's not so difficult.
実力が拮抗してればなお更でしょう
And it's even more true between
two drivers with similar skills.
逆に言えば 見せないことは駆け引きにもなる
Conversely, hiding skills can be the key.
You show your true braking skills when...
本気のブレーキングを見せる時は
勝負に行くときだ
...you decide to settle the match.
遅れた
I was late, only a little, but definitely late.
ほんの少しだけど 確実に
先のロングストレートからハートブレーキング
That hard braking from the long straightaway...
たった一回切りだけど
Even if it was just that one time,
I was late in braking.
ブレーキングで遅れた
スゲー　突っ込み
Incredible entry !
The gap with the Eight-Six is getting wider !
ハチロクとの差が開き始めてるぞ
百パーセントガチンコのモードで
I'm using everything
I've got at 100% capacity.
デンジャラスゾーンに突入だぜ
I'm in a dangerous zone.
きてまっせ すぐそこまで
They're getting closer...
They're almost at the corner...
Looks quite dangerous.
見るからに危なげな動きに見えますけど
あの時代の車は足を固めていくと あいう挙動になるんですわ
The cars of that era tend to behave like
that when their suspension is stiffened.
ハチロクらしいと言えばらしいんやけど
You can say it's very 86-like.
あれは平均スピード百キロ以下のステージ限定で
The car's seriously tuned to be the very best in the stages
where the average speed is below 100km/h (62mph).
最強を目指して 本気で作りこんでますわ
So there's a meaning to the
choice of using the Eight-Six...
ハチロクという車種の選択にも意味があるのが
涼介の考えそうなことだぜ
That's something Ryosuke would come up with.
空力系のパーツを一切排除してるあたり
He knows what he's doing based on the fact that
the car doesn't have any aerodynamic parts, but...
間違いなく確信犯やね
けど あのレベルになると
...the level of competition is so high that the cars will momentarily
reach their critical speed even during the slow-speed stage.
いくら低速ステージでも
瞬間的には途方もない速度に達しますよって
サーキット走行でなければ効かないと言われてるGTウイングも
People say the GT wing only works on the circuit,
but at their level, it's no longer a decoration.
あのレベルになれば ただの飾りじゃおまへん
勝負の分岐点は空力かもしれまへんな
Aerodynamics might decide
the outcome of this race.
マツダの後輪駆動は
Basically, Mazda's rear-wheel drive cars are designed
to have the roll axis a little forward of the mid-point.
基本的にロール軸は前下がりに設計されているのが特徴なんだ
The FD is no exception, but the Roadster in particular gives you
a better handling feel thanks to the biased load to the front.
FDも同様ですが
特にロードスターはフロント荷重で舵の効きをよくして
ハンドリングに軽快感を出してますからね
だけど攻め込んでいけば
But if you push it harder, it tends to over-steer
because of the lack of load to the rear.
リアの荷重不足でオーバーステアが出てくる
ロードスターをチューニングしていくうえでは
It becomes an unavoidable
issue when tuning a Roadster.
それが一つのテーマになる
やり方は色々あるだろうけど
There are many different approaches, but you can't
eliminate the car's natural over-steering tendency.
基本的に素性としてオーバーステア出易い点は変えられない
そのあたりどういう処理をしているのか
I wonder how they dealt with it.
ダウンヒルでオーバーステアはまずいよな
Over-steering on the downhill is bad.
むしろアンダーステアのほうがはるかに速く走れる
Instead, you can drive faster by under-steering.
あれだけの相手だからな
Knowing our opponents, their car
must have been perfectly tuned, but...
車は完璧に仕上がってると思うが
If something destroys that balance,
Fujiwara will have a chance.
何かの拍子にバランスが崩れるようなことがあれば
藤原にとってはチャンスなんだが
追いつかね
I can't catch him, but...
けど
差が広がってもいなり
...the gap hasn't widened, even though
I'm only tracing his car's line and speed.
前の車のラインとスピードをトレースしてるだけなのに
そこまで走れるとは
It's almost a miracle that you've kept up with me.
ある意味奇跡だな
ここから先バックミラーは用なしだ
From this point on,
I don't need the mirror.
ここまで来れば もう駆け引きもない
No need to play a guessing game. I just
have to look ahead and keep pushing hard.
ただひたすら前を向いて攻めるだけだ
後ろを気にするのはゴールに飛び込んでから
I'll just have to check the
rear after crossing the goal line.
そのとき俺は勝っている
That's when I'll ensure my victory.
The Eight-Six's headlights went off !
消えた ハチロクのヘッドライトが
冗談じゃねえぞ この真っ黒な峠道で
No way ! On this pitch-black
mountain pass ? What's going on ?
何が起こってるんだ
ハチロクのヘッドライトが消えた
The Eight-Six's headlights are off ?!
ブラインドアタックか
The blind attack, huh ?
Ryosuke...
涼介さん
恐らく藤原ここまでの競り合いで
During the race until now, Fujiwara must have intuitively
learned that he's at a disadvantage in the high-speed sections.
高速区間では不利なことを感覚的に察したんだろう
藤原独特の天恵
Fujiwara's god sent talent...
No, he may have heard
the voice of the Eight-Six.
いいや　ハチロクの声を聞いたのかもしれない
ブラインドアタック
Blind attack, which is Fujiwara's forte, is a two-sided
diversion technique of confusing his opponent...
藤原が得意とするこの技は
相手を動揺させると同時に攻撃ルートを悟らせないという
二重の効果を狙った陽動作戦だ
...as well as hiding his offensive strategy.
だがコースを熟知し なおかつ相手が異常に集中している時は
But when the opponent is familiar with
the course and remains highly focused...
そうだ　狙ったはずの効果は生み出されない
Right. It doesn't create the desired effect.
However...
しかし
リトラクタブルのヘッドライトは
Retractable headlights have a lower drag
coefficient value when they're lowered.
上げた状態よりも
下げたほうがCD値が下がる
空気抵抗が少なくなりますからね
Because of less air resistance.
わずかながらも空気抵抗を減らすことにより
Fujiwara must have wanted to raise his top speed by
reducing the drag, even if only by a very small amount.
トップスピードを稼ぎたいという気持ちが
藤原にそれをさせたんだ
執念か 藤原の
Fujiwara's tenacity ?
その執念が突破口を
His tenacity might create...
開くことになるかもしれない
...a breakthrough.
ブレーキングを開始するほんのわずかに手前
Just before his braking action...
よく分かねえけど
I'm not exactly sure, but most likely...
たぶん ここだ
Right here.
速かった
It was too soon, if only by a little.
ほんの少し
一体何が起こった
What the hell happened ?
くそ 負けっかよ ここまで来て
Dammit, I won't lose after coming this far.
俺のスペースはきっちりもらうぜ
I'll keep my space.
Can you keep up ?
着いて来れっかよ
ウイングをやっちまった
I messed up the wing.
I've gotta keep the race short.
これは長びかせるわけにはいかない
一本目で 絶対に終わらせるぜ
I'll settle this match on the first run.
車が妙なふらつき方をする
The car is unstable.
ウイングがどうなってるのか知らないが
I don't know what's wrong with the wing,
but the car's lateral balance is off.
左右のバランスがおかしいぜ
いっそのことちぎれて吹っ飛んでくれたほうがましだったな
I would've been better off if
it had broken off completely.
くそ　言い訳はしないぜ
Damn, no need for excuses. I just have
to motivate myself to raise my limit.
気合で限界を上げりゃいい
今日は俺の日じゃ
So, today wasn't my day after all.
なかったってことか
Fujiwara Takumi:
Takahashi Ryosuke:
Takahashi Keisuke:
Uehara Mika:
Miki Shinichiro
Koyasu Takehito
Seki Tomokazu
Hayami Saori
Omiya Satoshi:
Eiji Kubo:
Gou Hojo:
Kobayakawa:
Tochi Hiroki
Kase Yasuyuki
Kiuchi Hidenobu
Hamada Kenji
Fumihiro:
Matsumoto:
Kenta:
Mechanic:
246A:
246B:
Gallery:
Hosoi Hajime
Nishi Ryotaro
Okano Kosuke
Takahashi Ryokichi
Maeda Hiroki
Murakami Yuya
Asari Ryota
Following the brake light of the front car.
Falling perfect lighten the focal
A shimmering light up ahead in the dark street.
暗い道の先にぼんやりにじむ明かり
It's the silence like a silent film.
If the tires strike a silent wind
A
Central Anime
Production
Translation:
Hiro-kun
Timing:
Todd Perkins
Editing:
Barbara
Todd Perkins
Brain
Dave
Mouse
The light was all I could depend on.
頼りになるものはそれしか見えなかった
この並木道を抜けていけばきっと
I felt like I could catch it...
...if I passed through this tree-lined street.
つかめるような気がした
Give up! I just can't understand
Get up! I just can't understand.
I couldn't find what I'd been looking for.
外にはまだ捜し物は何もなくて
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
At this place.
この場所から
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf
I lost my way.
I lost my way
白く曇った窓と的外れなNavigation
Fogged up windows, and...
...messed up navigation.
赤く変わった信号で
As the stoplight turns red...
サイドミラーに映る視界を遮るLight
...a light in the side mirror blinds my eyes.
冷たい風が入り込まないように
I gradually close the window...
窓をそっと締めたんだ
...to stop the cold wind from blowing in.
Get up! I just can't understand.
Give up! I just can't understand
そこに広がる道を選んで進む僕は
We must choose one of the paths that lie ahead.
Yeah, it starts at this moment.
Yeah! It stops at this moment
Because you're with me.
君がいるなら
Please turn over the flyleaf.
Please stand alone on the flyleaf